Contact

9792036661 (Mobile) tyleraharrison@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tylerharrison-895486ab (LinkedIn) tylerharrison.dev (Personal)

Top Skills

Python C++ 3D Printing

Tyler Harrison

Computer Information Systems Major & AI / Cybersecurity Research Assistant @ Texas A&M University - Commerce College Station

Summary

With the growing threat of cyber-attacks, I've dedicated my academic career to AI and cybersecurity so that I can gain the tools needed to aid in solving this problem. Cybersecurity, artificial intelligence, and automation are all ground-breaking technologies, with just as many threats as there are benefits. I'm currently researching methods to assist in combating future cyberattacks.

Currently working on:

BS in Computer Information Systems at Texas A&M - Commerce Context-aware AI research with Dr. Eman Hammad (iSTAR Labs) Knowledge graph-based approach to cyber-security threat evaluation Cyber-range development using exclusively open-source software

Programming Experience:

C++ and Object-Oriented Programming
ARM Assembly programming (programmed for ARM Cortex v6 chips)

Java programming for robotic systems (WPILib)
Python web scraping (Selenium)
Arduino C

Hardware Experience:

3D Printing/CNC with Fusion 360 and Autodesk Inventor Open-source 3D printing firmware (Marlin/PrusaSlicer) Arduino-based hardware development

Software Tool Experience:

Linux/Bash (Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora, PopOS)

Networking and KVM Management (libvirt, Bind, Tomcat, Apache Guacamole, Foreman)

Web server management (Apache, PHP, MySQL)

Web server management (Apache, PHP, MySQL)

Microsoft Office Suite

Amazon Web Services Deployment

Google Cloud VM Management

Group coordination over Microsoft Teams, GitHub, Trello, Discord, Slack, Telegram, etc.

Management of GitHub repositories and organizations

Experience

H-E-B HEB Partner June 2018 - Present (3 years 1 month) College Station

Fulshear Ace Hardware Sales Associate June 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Maintain technology, organize spreadsheets and data, manage inventory, etc. Assist clients with issues utilizing training and experience.

Furious Falcons (Foster High School Robotics Team)
Lead Programmer (Alumnus)
August 2014 - May 2018 (3 years 10 months)
4400 FM 723 Rd, Richmond, TX 77406

Former lead programmer for the Furious Falcons FIRST Robotics team.

Trained new programmers to take over when I left. This consists of logic calculation, trig, algebra and basic mathematics, control structures, variables, custom libraries and interacting with the design team to program before the robot is created. The robots in the past that I have programmed from scratch have included advanced vision processing, co-processor interaction, custom PID loop control structures and basic autonomous tasks such as moving boxes and shooting balls into targets. I currently program in Java, C and some C# (Unity) and will be expanding to C++ in the future.

Education

Texas A&M University-Commerce

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer and Information Systems Security/ Information Assurance · (January 2021 - May 2023)

Blinn College

Associate of Science - AS, Computer and Information Systems Security/ Information Assurance · (August 2018 - May 2021)

Foster High School High School Diploma, Computer Science · (2014 - 2018)